<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Miscellaneous &#8211; Real Raec</title>
	<atom:link href="https://realraec.xyz/category/miscellaneous/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://realraec.xyz/</link>
	<description>Not that my opinion matters anyway.</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sun, 02 Jul 2023 22:47:53 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.2.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://realraec.xyz/wp-content/uploads/RR-Logo-64x64-1.png</url>
	<title>Miscellaneous &#8211; Real Raec</title>
	<link>https://realraec.xyz/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Starting Point</title>
		<link>https://realraec.xyz/starting-point/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[realraec]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2016 06:15:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Miscellaneous]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://realraec.xyz/?p=39</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[(Oh my. Am I actually doing this? This is so exciting... But damn! the pressure is real. 'And the knees go shakity-shake', haha. A brand-new blog, a kickass domain name, an overwhelming enthusiasm... What could possibly be missing? Oh, yes, an audience. The more I think about it though, the more I am convinced it [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<pre>(Oh my. Am I actually doing this? This is so exciting... But damn! the pressure is real. 'And the knees go shakity-shake', haha.
A brand-new blog, a kickass domain name, an overwhelming enthusiasm... What could possibly be missing? Oh, yes, an audience. The more I think about it though, the more I am convinced it is better this way. For now, at least. I mean, would you want thousands of people listening to you play the violin if you couldn't hit a note right? Me neither.)</pre>
<h2>Because this thing has to start somewhere</h2>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Here we are. You, me, the world. So many people with so many ideas, opinions, emotions. The question is, why should you care about me, about mine? You shouldn&#8217;t, that&#8217;s the point. Pretty&nbsp;ironic, isn&#8217;t it? (For the one writing to tell the one reading, you know.) Understand that I am nothing but a regular guy wandering&nbsp;in the immensity of everything else. I am no special snowflake, this blog is not to be a tribute to my genius. I would get&nbsp;bored, and so would you. After all, you did come here, and I feel like you are entitled to be entertained. I want to write, you want to read. Looks like we&#8217;re the perfect match, darling.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">I don&#8217;t have a gift with words, and sometimes I just can&#8217;t&nbsp;say what&#8217;s on my mind, plus&nbsp;my thoughts aren&#8217;t better than anyone else&#8217;s — that&#8217;s for sure. Yet I like to think&nbsp;that I am somehow worth reading&#8230; For I write with <em>love</em>, and I truly believe in its power of making everything better&#8230; Nah, just kidding. Enough with those pseudo-powerful four-letter words already. Who cares what I think&nbsp;I am worth? Read my&nbsp;articles and think for yourself. By the way, something you need to know for the future: I hate it when bloggers, youtubers, whateverers&nbsp;ask their audience&nbsp;to &#8216;like, share, and subscribe&#8217;. Seriously, fuck this, fuck them. You&#8217;re grown-ups, for heaven&#8217;s&nbsp;sake, you know what to do if you want to do it. I&#8217;ve had enough of all this &#8216;spread the word&#8217;, &#8216;do you agree? leave a comment&#8217;, &#8216;subscribe to my channel and I&#8217;ll subscribe to yours&#8217; bullshit. You will see none of this here. And if you do, I give you my permission to kill me with fire. Actually, that&#8217;s an order. I mean it.</p>
<div id="attachment_16" style="width: 210px" class="wp-caption alignright"><a href="https://realraec.xyz/wp-content/uploads/startingpoint_original_calvinandhobbes.bmp" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-16" decoding="async" class="wp-image-16 size-full" src="https://realraec.xyz/wp-content/uploads/startingpoint_calvinandhobbes.png" alt="starting_point_hobbes" width="200" height="250"></a><p id="caption-attachment-16" class="wp-caption-text">Calvin &amp; Hobbes &#8211; November 18, 1985 &#8211; © Bill Watterson</p></div>
<p style="text-align: justify;">As this is my first-ever article — and because it&#8217;s kind of what this blog is supposed to be all about — allow me to share the final panel of the first strip of <strong></strong><strong><a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/24812.The_Complete_Calvin_and_Hobbes" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Calvin &amp; Hobbes</a></strong>, aka the very moment the magic was born. For&nbsp;it&#8217;s&nbsp;pretty much&nbsp;what made me want to do all this. Not because I believe that I deserve to be listened to, but because I believe works of art of this kind (whatever their nature, as you shall see)&nbsp;deserve to be talked about. And worshiped, but that might just be me. Anyway, the&nbsp;very fact that&nbsp;you are on this blog now means that you have ended up on the dark side of the Internet. Yet&nbsp;again, I guess you can find what you are looking for&nbsp;there too.</p>
<p>So, welcome aboard, then?</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
